Aqsa Akhtar (Data Scientist/Analyst)

Phone: 07767 136938 (Reading, Berkshire, UK)

Email: agsa.akhtar31@gmail.com (Eligible to work in the UK)



PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a passionate Data Scientist/Analyst with more than two years of experience in data processing, manipulation, visualization, along with the optimization of machine learning algorithms. I am looking forward to an opportunity that can challenge my technical skills and help me grow.

PROJECTS

Data Analysis and Reporting (PESB, London)

Analyzed data in text files that are output from a calculation software program built by PESB a trading company based in London. Python, SQL, Power BI

Cricket match Scores prediction

A calculation tool to predict scores and possible results of a limited-overs match using linear regression. The prediction was based upon factors like the pitch condition, weather, and total boundaries by a team, etc. Tools used were Weka, R, and Tableau.

Insurance Policy

Constructed a model which predicts whether or not a customer has bought a policy using a machine learning algorithm. Logistic regression was used to predict the target variable. Programming languages used were Python (Pandas, Numpy, Scikitlearn, seaborn, and matplotlib), SQL.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist/Analyst - Self Employed (Dec 2019 – Date)

Worked on various projects including detection of fake vs real images and Analysis of campaign ran by a media agency.

Data Scientist Research Associate – ITU (January 2017- June 2018)

Published a conference and Journal Paper using Twitter data, cleaned and processed in languages like Python and SQL. Applied Machine Learning Models such as SVM, Random Forest, Decision Tree, Linear Regression, along with the visualization in Tableau/Power BI.

- Visiting Faculty Computer Applications- University of Management and Technology (Feb 2018- Feb 2019) - Advanced Excel for Analysis
- Lab/Teacher Instructor ITU (February' 18 June' 18) Database/SQL

DATA SCIENCE FOCUSED RESEARCH PUBLICATIONS

- Conference Paper: Exploiting Social Networks of Twitter in Altmetrics Big Data, *Published in 23rd* International Conference on Science and Technology Indicators (STI 2018), The Netherlands.
- Journal Paper: Influential Tweeters in Relation to Highly Cited Papers in Altmetric Big Data, Published in 119th Volume of Springer Scientometrics Journal,

EDUCATION

2015 – 2017 Master of Science in Computer Science – Information Technology University, Pakistan

2011 – 2015 Bachelor's in Computer Science – National University of Computer and Emerging Science, FAST

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

Tableau 2020 A-Z: Hands-On Tableau Training for Data Science (2021) – *Online Course (Udemy)* Tableau Training (2021) - *Online Course* (Simplilearn)

Microsoft Power BI Desktop for Business Intelligence (2021) – *Online Course (Udemy)*

SKILLS

Python Scikit Learn Machine Learning Pandas Numpy Matplotlib Power BI SPSS Jupyter Notebook Tableau